theglobesailor.com 2019-04-10

# Terms & Conditions | GlobeSailor

This privacy and protection of personal data policy describes what types of personal data GLOBESAILOR may collect from you and how GLOBESAILOR, its subsidiaries, contractors and partners may be allowed to use it. This policy also provides you with important information about your rights and the protection of your personal data. All transactions of your personal data are carried out in compliance with the regulations in effect and with the law n° 78-17 « Data Processing, Files and Freedom » amended on January 6, 1978.

### 1\. Who is collecting your data?

Your personal data is collected by GLOBESAILOR S.A.S., simplified joint stock company, with capital of 14,329.00 euros, 141 av de Clichy - 75017 Paris - France, RCS Nanterre with number 489 893 909.

### 2\. Personal data collected

The concept of "Personal Data" means any information relating to an actual person identified or who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identification number or to one or more elements of their own. When GLOBESAILOR collects your personal data, this collection is carried out in a transparent manner thanks to the presence of information or reference to this Policy. Personal Data is the information that identifies you such as civility, first and last name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number(s), username and password of your GLOBESAILOR account and any other personal data useful for the purposes set out in Chapter 3 of this Policy. Your personal data is collected either via our forms, when you register for your GLOBESAILOR space, or when you browse our sites. No matter on which device the data is collected, mandatory fields are indicated in the forms. If you do not wish to provide such information, you will not be able to access certain services or features of our websites. In addition, you may not be allowed purchase products or services through our websites. Other information, such as your sailing resume, is meant to get to know you better and is therefore optional. You are not obliged to provide it. GLOBESAILOR will take all necessary steps to ensure that the personal data processed is accurate and, if necessary, updated.

### 3\. For what purpose is personal data collected?

GLOBESAILOR commits to collect and process only Personal Data which is adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purposes for which it is collected. Your Personal Data is collected and used to access the features and services offered on our websites and maintain current, correct and relevant information about you, to meet one or more of the following purposes: a) Respond to your requests for quotes, information or contact to rent a boat, book a cruise or more widely benefit from our services. b) Allow you to create and use your GLOBESAILOR space c) Offer to respond to surveys that will allow us to improve and adapt our products and services d) Allow you to make an online booking of a quote or an available offer e) Offer you promotions or special offers that may interest you in our marketing operations

### 4\. Recipients of personal data

GLOBESAILOR may share your personal data with group companies, service providers (insurance companies) and its partner boat rental companies. For example: to validate your reservation, edit a rental contract or arrange your arrival at the rental base. The latter are bound by contract to respect the confidentiality and the security of your personal data which they are likely to receive and to use it exclusively within the framework of the services which they have been entrusted by GLOBESAILOR. In the event that your personal data is transferred to subcontractors residing outside the European Union, if necessary, a contract for the transfer of the personal data is signed by the subcontractor in order to maintain a similar level of protection of your personal data to that of GLOBESAILOR and European legislation. Except in the cases stated above, GLOBESAILOR also agrees not to sell, rent, or transfer your personal data to third parties without your consent. GLOBESAILOR may be required to disclose your personal data without your prior consent in order to comply with a legal requirement. GLOBESAILOR may disclose your personal data if necessary to comply with a court summons, warrant or other judgment of order, which appears to be valid or to an authority that has asserted its legitimate authority to obtain the information in the context of an inquiry or in the exercise of a legitimate interest and in particular the defense of its rights.

### 5\. Retention period of personal data

GLOBESAILOR will keep your personal data in a secure environment for the time necessary to achieve the purposes for which they were collected or during the minimum retention period provided by the applicable legislation, particularly in civil and commercial matters.

### 6\. Security and confidentiality

GLOBESAILOR takes protective measures to ensure the confidentiality and security of your personal data and to prevent such data from being damaged, deleted or accessed by unauthorized third parties. Access to personal data is strictly limited to employees who are authorized by virtues of their duties and who are bound by an obligation of confidentiality.

### 7\. Right of access, modification and opposition

In accordance with articles 38, 39 and 40 of the law n ° 78-17 relating to technology, data, and individual liberties of January 6, 1978, you have a right to access, modify, or oppose the information concerning you. With proof of your identity, you can at any time verify the accuracy or request the correction, update, or deletion of your personal data. When your request is for information about you not to be used for commercial purposes, you have a legitimate right of objection without it being necessary to specify the basis of your request. If you have a GLOBESAILOR account, you can exercise your rights of access, modification, and update by logging into your account. Otherwise, you can exercise your rights of access, modification, and opposition, by writing to us at the following address: GLOBESAILOR Customer Relationship Service, 141 av de Clichy, 75017 PARIS.

### 8\. Cookies

GLOBESAILOR sites use cookies to adapt to the preferences of its users and to optimize its Internet pages. In order for you to connect to and customize the site and services, the site's webpage servers may place cookies on your computer. These cookies facilitate navigation and improve the user-friendliness of the website. For information about cookies, you can click here.

### 9\. Changes to the privacy policy

In the event that GLOBESAILOR modifies this policy or if the law requires to do so, it will be published on our websites and will be effective upon its publication. Therefore, we encourage you to refer to this publication each visit to learn more about the latest version which is permanently available on our websites.

To ensure the proper functioning of our site, we sometimes need to save small data files on the information and devices of our users. Most major websites do the same.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that websites store on your computer or mobile device when you use them. It allows sites to remember your actions and preferences (username, language, character size and other display settings) for a given time, so you do not have to re-enter this information each time you visit a site or navigate from one page to another.

### The cookies that we use allow us:

• to establish statistics and the use of various elements of our website (headings and content visited, preferred routes), allowing us to improve the interest and ergonomics of our services;   
• to adapt the presentation of our website to your device’s display preferences (language used, display resolution, operating system, etc.) during your visits to our site, depending on the hardware and software viewing or reading that your mobile device operates;   
• to memorize information relating to a form that you have completed on our site (registration or access to your account) or to products, services or information that you have shown a preference for on our website (subscribed service, favourites, etc.);   
• to allow you to access reserved and personal areas of our website, such as your account, using identifiers or data that you may have previously entrusted to us;   
• to implement security measures, for example, when you are asked to sign-in again to access content or a service after a certain amount of time.

### Cookies issued on our site by third parties

Our site may contain cookies issued by third parties (audience measurement companies, communication agencies, etc.) and allows these cookies, during the period of validity of said cookies, to collect browsing information about the devices which are consulting our website. The issue and use of cookies by third parties are subject to the privacy policies of these third parties. We inform you about the purpose of cookies that we know and the means you have to make choices about these cookies.

### Regarding third party applications integrated into our site

We may include third party computer applications on our site that allow you to share content from our site with other people or to let others know about your review or opinion about content from our site. This is particularly in the case of the "Share" and "Like" buttons, coming from social networks such as, but not limited to, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Viadeo, etc. The social network providing such an application button is likely to identify you because of a button like this, even if you may not have used this button during your visit to our site. In fact, this type of application button can allow the social network to follow your navigation on our site, just because your social network account was activated on your device (an open session) during your navigation on our site. We have no control over this process used by social networks to collect information about your navigation on our site and associated with the data. We invite you to consult the privacy policies of these social networks to learn about the purposes of use, including advertising, and navigation information they can collect through these application buttons. These protection policies must allow you to exercise your choices with these social networks, including setting up your usage accounts for each of these networks.

### How to control cookies

You can control and/or delete cookies as you choose. You have the option to delete all cookies already stored on your computer and configure most browsers to block them as well. However, if you choose the latter, you may need to manually enter your preferences or your information each time you visit a site, and some services and features may not be accessible. 

For the management of cookies and your choices surrounding cookies, the configuration of each browser is different. It is described in the Help Menu of your browser, which will allow you to know how to change and manage your preferences for cookies. 

You can also connect to the site Youronlinechoices, proposed by digital advertising professionals grouped within the European association EDAA (European Digital Advertising Alliance). 

You will be able to know which companies are registered on this platform and which offer you the possibility of refusing or accepting their cookies: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>. 

This European platform is shared by hundreds of advertising professionals on the Internet. It is a centralized interface that allows you to express your refusal or your acceptance of cookies that can be used to adapt advertisements to a user’s type of device based on information collected from said cookies. Note that this procedure will not prevent advertisements from being displayed on the websites you visit; it will only block the technology that will tailor advertisements to your interests.
